A Guide to the Frederick M. Bohen papers FA1397
Rockefeller Archive Center
Frederick M. Bohen papers
1959-1989
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bohen, Fred
FA1397
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
Scope and Contents
The collection primarily comprises a copy of Fred Bohen's college thesis -- his advisors were McGeorge Bundy and Zbigniew Brzezinski -- and papers from his work with the Ford Foundation including correspondence, memoranda, chronological files, policy planning documents, and public interest advocacy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to RAC by Kim Bohen in 2017 and transferred as Accession 2017:044.
Related Materials
In additional to Bohen's work with the Rockefeller University and the Ford Foundation available at the Rockefeller Archive Center, Bohen papers at other libraries and archives include:
Material documenting his White House years, 1966-1968 is available at the Lyndon B. Johnson Presidential Library.
Material from his work at the Public Broadcast Laboratory, 1968-1970 is available at the University of Maryland Libraries Special Collections in Mass Media and Culture.
Material documenting his two congressional campaigns, 1972 and 1974, is available at the Rutgers University Archives.
Ford Foundation
- Frederick M. Bohen - Thesis - "Limited Disarmament with Disengagement in Europe", Department of Government, Harvard, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association - Papers, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The President's Departmental Reorganization Program - The Proposed Department of Human Resources: A Summary, 1971 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The President's Advisory Council on Executive Organization - Memorandum for the President of the United States - Establishment of a Department of Natural Resources: Organization for Social and Economic Programs, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Statement by McGeorge Bundy to the Commission for the Organization of Government for the Conduct of Foreign Policy, 1973 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bundy-Ford Foundation Correspondence - Pending Correspondence, 1966-1973, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Personal - Correspondence - Heineman, Ben W., 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Clippings, Grant Proposal to the Kellogg Foundation, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from Bundy to Bohen, 1984 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Frederick M. Bohen Correspondence 1969-1970 - Chronological File - Ford Foundation (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bundy, McGeorge - Memoranda, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- University Programs of Training and Research in Public Policy, A Report to the Trustees, Ford Foundation, 1971 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Preliminary Draft: University Programs of Training and Research in Public Policy Studies, Ford Foundation, 1971 December (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Planning for the Foundation's Program in 1973 and Beyond, Ford Foundation, 1972 March (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Foundation's Tax Exempt Status (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Public Interest Advocacy, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence - Charitable Status of Private Litigation to Protect the Environment, 1970 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Frederick M. Bohen Correspondence 1971-1972 - Chronological File - Ford Foundation (Box 1, Folder 18)